Literatura de Cordel collection, 1918-1995
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Profane Tales., 1918-1995.
  - Title: A sinistra morte de Aldo Moro Author: Francisco Sales Arêda Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: Se o homem tivesse rabo Author: Silva Neto (JUCA) Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Gráfica Aurora Ltda., after 1950. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: As proezas da besta-feira Author: Jaiel de Assis Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: A pega do barbatão Author: Juvenal Evangelista Santos Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: Vida e imortalidade de Alfredo Nasser Author: Paulo Nunes Batista Publisher: P. N. Batista., 13/09/78. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: Vida e morte de Helena do bode a gorda macumbeira baiana Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Other: acrostic MAXADO., fevereiro 1980. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Cover contains a photo of women practicing Macumba. The rear wrapper contains an advertisement for Ron Bacardi.
  - Title: Vamos dar o calote para sobrevivermos Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Other: acrostic MAXADO., junho de 1983. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: Vaquejada de sete peões prá derrubar uma mineira Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Other: acrostic MAXADO., março de 1976. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Title: Pirajá o mito da capoeira Author: Casmiro Junior e Admilson Barros Publisher: Conselho de Moradodes do morro da Conceição., 1982. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Um cachorro que fez mal a duas moças Author: Severino Marques de Souza Junior, aka Palito Illustrator: signed PALITO Publisher: Palito Other: acrostic PALITO., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Como e porque Eno Teodoro Wanke tornou-se meu biógrafo Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante., ca. 1980. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A cura de um alcóolatra Author: Romildo Santos Illustrator: José Costa Leite signed JCL Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Other: acrostic ROMILDO., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: O covarde marinheiro que salvou a tripulação do seu navio Author: Romildo Santos Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Considerações de uma poetisa pela Feira de Fagundes Author: Zaíra Dantas da Silva Publisher: unknown., 4 de janeiro de 1972. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Caboclinhos Author: V. Licarião Illustrator: signed MA 76 Publisher: unknown., ca. 1976. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Cavalho Velho Author: Zé Gomes, o vaqueiro jaboatão Publisher: unknown., 1971. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: O cangaceiro na roça Author: José Cavalcanti e Ferreira Dila Illustrator: signed AUTOR DILA Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic JCFDILA., ca. 1970s. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Cangaceiro do coronel eudócio Author: José Cavalcanti e Ferreira Dila um ex-cangaceiro Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: Gráfica Felipe Saboia Other: 2nd edition., 12/2/1982. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Folheto sobre o 1o congresso dos poetas da literatura de cordel...o congresso dos poetas e os atos de um principe Author: Elias A. de Carvalho Publisher: E. A. de Carvalho., junho de 1978. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Colegio da UF de Pernambuco Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Publisher: R. Santa Helena., 9 de maio 1983. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A cara testamento Getúlio Vargas 100 anos 1883 - 1983 Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Publisher: R. Santa Helena., 19/4/83. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: O casamento do lobisomem com a vampira feiticeira Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: F. M. Nordestino., 1980. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Saci e bicho folharaz no reino da bicharada Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Other: acrostic MAXADO., janeiro de 1977. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Meia noite no cabarét Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: signed but illegible Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 26/4/76. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: O matuto vendendo fumo ambulante Author: unknown Illustrator: signed STENIO Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 05/09/76. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A fada do nevoeiro Author: Dr. Ernesto Véra Publisher: Typ. Guajarina., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: O forro da bicharada Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed MARCELO Publisher: A.A. dos Santos Other: acrostic AALVES., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A foice da morte Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed Ciro Publisher: Folhetaria Santos Other: acrostic AALVES., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Festa das faixas 1957 - 1976 bi-super campeão Author: Domingo Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda., ca. 1976. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Feitos da revolução e reformas políticas Author: José Soares Publisher: unknown., 15/4/77. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: As meninas do sertão são iguais as de Ipanema Author: Raimundo Silva Publisher: R. Silva Other: acrostic RSILVA., 15 de novembro de 1983. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A morte de Pedro Nava Author: Sá de João Pessoa Publisher: unknown., 18/5/84. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Maluf que me desculpe mas sou baiano também Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Other: acrostic MAXADO., 22/8/84. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Mário Melo centenário do seu nascimento 1884 - 1984 Author: FUNDARPE Publisher: H. R. Barros. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A morte e os feitos de Zezinho do Bazar, José Soares Filho Author: Manoel Leite Filho Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Meu estágio na emergência da restauração em 1976 Author: M. Mabel de L. Ramos Illustrator: Ivana Ramos Publisher: unknown., after 1976. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A mulher do compadre Nicoláu Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Other: 2nd Edition., ca. 1970. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: O maquinista da RFFSA Author: José Caetano da Silva Illustrator: signed Tio Gu Publisher: Gutemberg Liberato de Andrade., 25/09/82. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A mocidade de hoje no goso da beira-mar Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Meu navio brasileiro Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed NB Publisher: J.C. Leite Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., ca. 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: As moças dizem aos rapazes casar ligeiro é assim Author: José Alves Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: A mulher no lugar do homem Author: José Pacheco Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Um matuto na cidade Author: João Vicente Emiliano Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Mulher ciumenta Author: Bernardino de Sena Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Muda Brasil com Tancredo na presidencia um sonho de um poeta no colégio eleitoral Author: Leonardo Publisher: unknown., ca. 1984. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Um médico do poco para fortalecer a organização popular Author: Hermenegilda da Costa Silva Illustration: signed A.F. Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Version española de Helena Ferreira Malvinas Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustration: signed A.F. Publisher: unknown., 16/1/1984. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Title: Lampião não era tão cão como se pinta Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustration: signed JRS Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante., 1982. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Lampião na Bahia Author: Jose Bernardo da Silva Illustration: signed STENIO Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 10/01/82. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Salve a rua preta Author: Liberato Filho Illustration: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: O pensamento de um poeta Author: Waldelene Cristóvão Illustrator: signed WALÉRIO Publisher: Folhetaria São Cristóvão., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: História do Poeta Barbosa, o martizado Author: Severino Barbosa Torres Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: É triste o homem cair nas garras do alcoolismo Author: Severino Cesário da Silva Illustrator: signed JOAO Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda Other: acrostic CESARIO., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Literatura de cordel o prenúncio do fim Author: Marcelo Soares Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: M. Soares., Maio 1980. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: O leão tirou a titica campeão 77 Author: José Soares Publisher: unknown., 16/10/77. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Lembrança de Manoel Raimundo de Souza Author: Manoel Raimundo de Souza Publisher: Gráfica Júlio Costa., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Lampião e a velha feiticeira Author: José Pacheco Illustrator: unsigned, José Costa Leite Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Uma pescaria em boqueirão a vara, o anzol e o minhocão Author: Caetano Cosme da Silva Illustrator: signed CCS Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic CAETANO., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: O corre-corre de um barraqueiro Author: Antonio Silva Vilas Boas Publisher: unknown., 1980. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A camisa do homem feliz Author: Agenôr de Jesus Silva Faria Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Cordel da Rosa do Mar ou da bira bar Author: Aybirê Ferreira de Sá Publisher: unknown., 19 de janeiro de 1983. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A corrupção no Ceará e a intervenção imprevisivel do governador em Juazeiro do norte Ceará Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Other: 2nd edition., outubro 1975. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Crime de piedade e terror revolta o povo de vicência, criança violentada com 3 anos de idade Author: Aldemar Sebastião Alves Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Praia verão Author: CALUMBI Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Poetas de Caruaru Author: Ciron Lopes, Rafael Barros, José Helio Publisher: Casa de Cultura José Condé, Prefeitura Municipal de Caruaru., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Por causa da carestia o pobre aperta a barriga Author: Palito Illustrator: signed PALITO Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic PALITO., after 1950. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Um cavalo bom de gado Author: Juvenal Evangelista Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A classificação do Santa e a repesca do Satanás Author: José Soares Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A chegada de Silvino na Vila Macaparana Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Lenda do Caipora Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: Tip Pontes., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Lenda do saci pererê Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: Tip Pontes., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Literatura de cordel Author: V. Licarião Illustrator: signed MA Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Literatura de cordel Author: Homero do Rêgo Barros Illustrator: signed MARCELO Publisher: unknown., 1977. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A lamentável morte do ex-presidente Humberto de Alencar Castelo Branco Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., ca. 1967. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A lamentável morte do Coronel Chico Heraclio Author: José Soares Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 18/12/74. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: O cavallo que defecava dinheiro Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda., 10/3/1976. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Um cordel para Olinda Author: Homero do Rêgo Barros Illustrator: signed PALITO Publisher: unknown., 1982. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Como se amança uma sogra Author: João Matins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 05/04/82. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: O Coronel Mangangá e o Seringueiro do Norte Author: Francisco Areda de Sales Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic F.SALES., 1900s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Catálago de A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: J. C. Leite Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., after 1960. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Caruaru de ontem e de hoje Author: José Severino Cristóvão Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: unknown Other: 5th edition., 1980. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Caruaru nordeste Author: José Severino Cristóvão Publisher: unknown Other: 6th edition., Agosto de 1982. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: A carta de um tabaréu segundo a língua caipira Author: João de Barros Illustration: signed J.B. Publisher: Folhetaria São João., after 1950. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Café rei do riso Author: João de Barros Illustration: signed JOTABARROS 75 Publisher: Folhetaria São João., 1975. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: Sonhos de um poeta na cidade do cordel Author: Fortes Sobrinho Publisher: João Alberto Lima Fortes., 1984. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Advertisements for Brahma on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Minha vida e minha filosofia Author: Lourival Bandeira Illustrator: signed Natanael 78 Publisher: Berto., 1978. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Title: O vôo da morte, historia completa do raid Havana Buenos Ayres Author: Dr. Ernesto Vera Publisher: Typographia da Guarjarina Place: Belem., 1900s. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Photo of three men on the wing of a plan called "Funkers" on front cover.
  - Title: Sozinho no mundo Author: Severino Borges Silva Illustrator: José Costa Leite signed JCL Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1950. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Title: A sorte d'uma meretriz Author: João Martins de Atayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Title: A segunda enchente do rio São Francisco e o medo do lapense Author: João Ferreira da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Title: O soldado jogador Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 25/2/60. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Title: A fabulosa estória de Roque Santeiro e de sua viúva, a que era sem nunca ter sido Author: Dias Gomes Illustrator: J. Borges Publisher: Rede Globo., ca 1970s. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Title: A morte dos 12 pares de frança Author: Marcos Sampaio Illustrator: signed Walderêdo Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 30/6/1973. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: O monstro, o indio e o menino Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: A moça que virou cachorra Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., after 1950. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: A moça que virou porca em Rio Tinto Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., after 1950. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: Interrogação Author: Oliveira Francisco de Panelas Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: História de Josina a menina perdida Author: unknown Publisher: João José da Silva., 1900s. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: O monstro de São Paulo Author: José Soares Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown., 31/8/77. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: A ladeira de 90 a 2000 Author: Severino Paulino da Silva Publisher: unknown., ca. 1980s. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Title: Debate de Natanael de Lima com Cirilo Vera Cruz Author: Natanael de Lima Illustrator: signed J.BARROS Publisher: Tip. Pontes Other: acrostic NDELIMA., after 1960. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Title: O automovel da morte Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed Ciro Publisher: Governo do Estado do Rio de Janeiro Other: acrostic A ALVES., after 1960. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O assassinato de João Caetano e a vingança do seu filho Oliveiros Author: Cipriano Barauna Publisher: A Estrella da Poesia Other: acrostic CIPRIANO Place: Guarabira., 10 de Set. de 1979. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: A marcha do desmantêlo Author: Erotildes Mirando dos Santos Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O sanfoneiro que foi tocar no inferno Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic JCOSTAL., 1973. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: A morte do Dr. Euclides Câmara Author: Manoel Leite Filho Publisher: M. L. Filho Cia Lida Place: Bezerros., 18/11/79. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem mal educado Author: José Bernardo da Silva Publisher: unknown Place: Juazeiro., 8/6/55. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Lampião governo geral do inferno Author: João Barros Illustrator: signed J.B. Publisher: Folhetaria São João Place: Bayeux Pb.., after 1960. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Os milagres em Sergipe, de um poeta que quase morre de fome na seca, hoje é célebre mundialmente Author: Téo Macedo Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: T. Macedo Place: São Paulo., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: A morte do Coroné Ludugero Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante and Manoel D'Almeida Filho Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, RODOLFO ALMEIDA., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O assassinato de João Caetano e a vingança do seu filho Oliveiros Author: Cipriano Barauna Publisher: A Estrella da Poesia Other: acrostic, CIPRIANO., 18/6/1977. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem da vaca e o poder da fortuna Author: Francisco Sales Arêda Illustrator: signed [Eliago?] Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, F.SALES., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O testamento da Cigana Esmeralda Author: Leandro Gomes de Barros Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 10/5/74. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O triunfo de pequena Author: João José da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: História da Paraíba em verso, folheto IV Author: Severino Sertanejo Publisher: A União CIA Editora., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: História da Paraíba em verso, folheto II Author: Severino Sertanejo Publisher: A União CIA Editora., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: A vingança de um filho Author: Enéias Tavares Santos Illustration: signed ETS Publisher: Fundação das Crianças de Olinda Other: acrostic, ENEIAS., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O povo abraça caria pela sua decisão Author: João Crispim Ramos Illustration: signed MAXADO Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, JCRAMOS., Maio de 1979. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Poema, Seu amigo e conterrâneo Author: Manoel Xudú, Francisco Gomes de Sá Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, JCRAMOS., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Note on rear wrapper: "Para Vereador vote assim, Sá ou 1612, e tenha um defesor na Câmera Municipal."
  - Title: A pobreza aperriada procurando a emergência Author: Leandro Simões da Costa Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte., 1980. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O orgulho de Roberto e a queda da maldição Author: Severino Carlos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: João Severo da Silva., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Serra branca é luz de amor Author: José Leocadio Bezerra (Zezinho) Publisher: Bolo de Goma., 16/04/82. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Literatura de cordel a seca do nordeste Author: Severino Borges Silva Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: unknown Place: Timbaúba, PE., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Minhas melhores poesias Author: Wandeleide Cristóvão Illustrator: José Cavalcanti e Ferreira Dila signed DILA Publisher: Folhetaria São Cristóvão Place: Caruaru, PE., março de 1980. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: A história de um Jeep que caiu dentro do açude com 4 pessoas em sossêgo e não morreu ninguem no dia 29-10-1975, mais um milagre de Frei Damião Author: Lucena Batista dos Santos Publisher: unknown. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: É a vontade do povo vai dar zebra no crato pra fazer um crato novo Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: unknown Other: 2a edição., 15 de novembro de 1976. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Reproduction of a voting ballot on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Agradecimento dos velhos aposentados a o Presidente da Republica Author: José Antonio Torres (Zê Catolê) Publisher: unknown., 08/5/78. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Maconha, fuma e cachaça Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: signed JRS Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante., 1981. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Calendário Brsileiro para 1982 Author: José Costa Leite Publisher: Tipografia Pontes. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: A segunda vida de cancão de fogo Author: Minelvino Francisco Silva Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada., ca. 1959. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: Encontro de cancão de fogo com Pedro Malazarte Author: Minelvino Francisco Silva Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada., ca. 1957. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title: O soldado francês ou o baralho sagrado Author: José Martins dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 15/6/1962. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: O homem da vaca e o poder da fortuna Author: Francisco Sales Arêda Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic F.SALES., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: A voz do sábio francês Author: José Costa Leite Publisher: unknown., after 1970. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: A voz de um fantasma Author: Sebastião Palmeira da Silva Illustrator: José Costa Leite signed JCL Publisher: Tipografia da Folhetaria Pontes., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: Alergia Author: Delarme Monteiro Illustrator: signed JERONIMO Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, Alergia., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: O ano nacional da criança Author: José João dos Santos (Azulão) Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, AZULAO., 8/6/79. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: Antologia poética Author: José Severino Cristóvão Publisher: unknown., 1983. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: Amanhecer no sertão Author: José Gomes da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte., after 1960. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: O advogado gago, eu e o mudo Author: José Severino Cristovão Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: A historia do marco brasileiro Author: José Bernardo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 25/9/55. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: História de Pedro Ferreira da Silva e os sofrimentos passados Author: Pedro Ferreira da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: História do assassinato do manoel machado e a vingança de seu filho Samuel Author: Joaquim Batista de Sena Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Other: acrostic, JOAQUIM BATISTA., 12/79. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: Antonio Silvino e o negro corrupião Author: Francisco Alves Martins Publisher: Severino Simião., 1900s. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: Tributo a Veranildo, historia completa do garoto que foi cruelmente assassinado em Cuite, PB em julho de 83 Author: Dinamérico Soares do Nascimento Publisher: Gráfica Vitória Ltda., ca. 1983. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: As travessuras de Pedro Malazartes é feio dar na mulher mas apanhar é pior Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Tipografia Pontes., after 1960. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title: O touro preto que engoliu o fazendeiro Author: Minelvino Francisco Silva Illustrator: signed GAL Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada., after 1960. (Box 6, Folder 2)